Guide to the Emil J. Dillon Papers, ca. 1873-1933
Department of Special Collections
- Series 1. Correspondence
  - Subseries 1. Letters, Telegrams, and Related Notes
    - Daily Telegraph [80 of 93]1917 Feb. 6 - March 7, Incl. descriptive lists, postcards, tls, an agreement, press cuttings, als, als [?], typescripts, a manuscript, offprints. (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Daily Telegraph [81 of 93]1917 March 15 - March 27, Incl. descriptive lists, postcards, tls, an agreement, press cuttings, als, als [?], typescripts, a manuscript, offprints. (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Daily Telegraph [82 of 93]1917 April 2 - June 21, Incl. descriptive lists, postcards, tls, an agreement, press cuttings, als, als [?], typescripts, a manuscript, offprints. (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Daily Telegraph [83 of 93]1917 August 24 - August 29; n.d., Incl. descriptive lists, postcards, tls, an agreement, press cuttings, als, als [?], typescripts, a manuscript, offprints. (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Daily Telegraph [84 of 93]1917 Oct. 26 - Dec. 28, Incl. descriptive lists, postcards, tls, an agreement, press cuttings, als, als [?], typescripts, a manuscript, offprints. (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Daily Telegraph [85 of 93]1918 Jan. 9 - Feb. 11, Incl. descriptive lists, postcards, tls, an agreement, press cuttings, als, als [?], typescripts, a manuscript, offprints. (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Daily Telegraph [86 of 93]1918 Feb. 6 - March 19, Incl. descriptive lists, postcards, tls, an agreement, press cuttings, als, als [?], typescripts, a manuscript, offprints. (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Daily Telegraph [87 of 93]1918 July 12 - Sept. 17; n.d. / n.y., Incl. descriptive lists, postcards, tls, an agreement, press cuttings, als, als [?], typescripts, a manuscript, offprints. (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Daily Telegraph [88 of 93]1918 [?] Sept. 18 - Dec. 5; n.d. / n.y., Incl. descriptive lists, postcards, tls, an agreement, press cuttings, als, als [?], typescripts, a manuscript, offprints. (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Daily Telegraph [89 of 93]1919 July [?] 1 [?] - Sept. 15, Incl. descriptive lists, postcards, tls, an agreement, press cuttings, als, als [?], typescripts, a manuscript, offprints. (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Daily Telegraph [90 of 93]1919 Sept. 24 - Sept. 30, Incl. descriptive lists, postcards, tls, an agreement, press cuttings, als, als [?], typescripts, a manuscript, offprints. (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Daily Telegraph [91 of 93]1919 Dec. 23; n.d., Incl. descriptive lists, postcards, tls, an agreement, press cuttings, als, als [?], typescripts, a manuscript, offprints. (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Daily Telegraph [92 of 93]1933 June 10, Incl. descriptive lists, postcards, tls, an agreement, press cuttings, als, als [?], typescripts, a manuscript, offprints. (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Daily Telegraph [93 of 93]1938 [?] Nov. 9 - 1939 Dec. 5; n.y., Incl. descriptive lists, postcards, tls, an agreement, press cuttings, als, als [?], typescripts, a manuscript, offprints. (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Daily Telegraph - Telegrams [1 of 18]1893 [?] Oct. 1 - 1894 Nov. [18-28 ?] (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Daily Telegraph - Telegrams [2 of 18]1895 Ju [ne / ly ?] 22 - 1896 Sept. 11 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Daily Telegraph - Telegrams [3 of 18]1896 Sept. 13 - 1897 Oct. [?] 30 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Daily Telegraph - Telegrams [4 of 18]1898 [month ?] 31 - 1899 March 7 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Daily Telegraph - Telegrams [5 of 18]1900 March [?] 1 - 1902 April 17 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Daily Telegraph - Telegrams [6 of 18]1903 Jan. 5 - March 24 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Daily Telegraph - Telegrams [7 of 18]1903 April 1 - May 18 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Daily Telegraph - Telegrams [8 of 18]1903 May 19 - June 11 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Daily Telegraph - Telegrams [9 of 18]1903 June 12 - August 4 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Daily Telegraph - Telegrams [10 of 18]1903 August 12 - Dec. 8 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Daily Telegraph - Telegrams [11 of 18]1903 Dec. 16 - Dec. 31 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Daily Telegraph - Telegrams [12 of 18]1904 Jan. 2 - 1908 May 7 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Daily Telegraph - Telegrams [13 of 18]1909 April 18 - 1922 [?]; n.d. (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Daily Telegraph - Telegrams [14 of 18]Dates are unreadable / illegible. (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Daily Telegraph - Telegrams [15 of 18]Dates are unreadable / illegible. (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Daily Telegraph - Telegrams [16 of 18]Dates are unreadable / illegible; n.d. (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Daily Telegraph - Telegrams [17 of 18]Dates are unreadable / illegible; n.d. (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Daily Telegraph - Telegrams [18 of 18]Dates are unreadable / illegible. (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Dalebrook, John1902 Nov. 8 - 1903 March 29 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Davidson, Arthur, Sir1917 June 21 (Box 11, Folder 20)
      Contains correspondence relating to Bismark.
    - Delcassé, [?] [1 of 2]18 [98-99 ?] [n.d.] - 1914 Nov. 30; n.d. (Box 11, Folder 21)
      Contains correspondence to Mr. Le Sage. Some materials are in French.
    - Delcassé, [?] [2 of 2]1914 Nov. 30 - 1916 Dec. 4 (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Delines, Michel[n.y.] July 30, Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 11, Folder 23)
      Contains correspondence relating to Turgenev. In French.
    - Dilke, Charles, Sir & Emilia, Lady [1 of 4]1887 April 27 - 1890 July 3, Incl. a descriptive list, tls, als [?], press cuttings. (Box 11, Folder 24)
      Contains materials relating to the King; Mark Pattison; George Eliot; Crawford; Gladstone; Cobben; Bright; Chamberlain. One press cutting is in French.
    - Dilke, Charles, Sir & Emilia, Lady [2 of 4]1890 Sept. 6 - 1901 May 11; n.d., Incl. a descriptive list, tls, als [?], press cuttings. (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Dilke, Charles, Sir & Emilia, Lady [3 of 4]1902 July 18 - 1905 June 21; n.d., Incl. a descriptive list, tls, als [?], press cuttings. (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - Dilke, Charles, Sir & Emilia, Lady [4 of 4]1994 Jan. 28; n.d. / n.y., Incl. a descriptive list, tls, als [?], press cuttings. (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - Dillon, John [1 of 7]1890 July 21 - 1898 March 25, Incl. a descriptive list, tls, press cuttings, obituaries. (Box 12, Folder 1)
      Contains materials relating to Elizabeth Dillon; Murray Butler; John Mitchel; Parnell; William O'Brien; Sir Edward Grey; Liakhoff; Witte; Shah.
    - Dillon, John [2 of 7]1902 Jan. 9 - 1903 Feb. 8, Incl. a descriptive list, tls, press cuttings, obituaries. (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Dillon, John [3 of 7]1905 Oct. 6 - 1909 July 12, Incl. a descriptive list, tls, press cuttings, obituaries. (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Dillon, John [4 of 7]1909 Sept. 5 - 1914 Oct. 30, Incl. a descriptive list, tls, press cuttings, obituaries. (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Dillon, John [5 of 7]1917 Feb. 16 - Dec. 29; n.d., Incl. a descriptive list, tls, press cuttings, obituaries. (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Dillon, John [6 of 7]1920 May 5 - 1927 August 5; n.d., Incl. a descriptive list, tls, press cuttings, obituaries. (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Dillon, John [7 of 7]1927 August 27; n.d. / n.y., Incl. a descriptive list, tls, press cuttings, obituaries. (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Dillon, Kathleen [1 of 31]1913 Dec. 16 - 1914 Oct. 22, Incl. als, tls, postcards. (Box 12, Folder 8)
      Contains materials relating to Miss Scott; Mrs. Lindsay; Lord Robert Cecil; Lord Hardinge; Lloyd George; Lord French; Dr. Felce; Frewens; Mrs. Tuck; Empress Eugene; Cooks; Mrs. Clayton; Lord Carnarvon; Mr. Asquith; Winston Churchill; Lord Dunraven; Lord Burnham; Desmond; Miss Fox; Mr. Smith; Lord Grimthorpe; the Princess of Moniko [Monako ?]; Mrs. Astor; Lady Cunard; Mrs. George Keppel; the French Ambassador; Miss Bird; Mrs. [?] Schwartz; the Prime Minister; M. Gutchkoff; Madame Muravieff; the Tsar and Tsarina [Tsaritsa]; Miss Fourneaux; Nikolai Pavdinskii; Katya; Count & Countess Oropeso; Mrs. Maguire; Lady Muriel Paget; Skriabin. One letter is in Russian.
    - Dillon, Kathleen [2 of 31]1914 Oct. 27 - 1915 Jan. 15, Incl. als, tls, postcards. (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Dillon, Kathleen [3 of 31]1915 April 22 - July 31, Incl. als, tls, postcards. (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Dillon, Kathleen [4 of 31]1915 August 4 - August 5, Incl. als, tls, postcards. (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Dillon, Kathleen [5 of 31]1915 August 6 - August 15, Incl. als, tls, postcards. (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Dillon, Kathleen [6 of 31]1916 Feb. 23 - August 17, Incl. als, tls, postcards. (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Dillon, Kathleen [7 of 31]1916 Sept. 17 - Oct. 30, Incl. als, tls, postcards. (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Dillon, Kathleen [8 of 31]1916 Oct. 31 - Nov. 1, Incl. als, tls, postcards. (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Dillon, Kathleen [9 of 31]1916 Nov. 3 - Nov. 5, Incl. als, tls, postcards. (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Dillon, Kathleen [10 of 31]1917 Jan. 23 - April 18, Incl. als, tls, postcards. (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Dillon, Kathleen [11 of 31]1917 April 19, Incl. als, tls, postcards. (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Dillon, Kathleen [12 of 31]1917 April 20 - April 24, Incl. als, tls, postcards. (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Dillon, Kathleen [13 of 31]1917 April 25 - April 28, Incl. als, tls, postcards. (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Dillon, Kathleen [14 of 31]1917 April 29 - May 1, Incl. als, tls, postcards. (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Dillon, Kathleen [15 of 31]1917 May 3 - May 6, Incl. als, tls, postcards. (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Dillon, Kathleen [16 of 31]1917 May 8 - May 10, Incl. als, tls, postcards. (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Dillon, Kathleen [17 of 31]1917 May 5 - May 15, Incl. als, tls, postcards. (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - Dillon, Kathleen [18 of 31]1917 May 16 - May 24, Incl. als, tls, postcards. (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - Dillon, Kathleen [19 of 31]1917 June 4 - July 1, Incl. als, tls, postcards. (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - Dillon, Kathleen [20 of 31]1918 March 30 [?] - 1921 Sept. 27, Incl. als, tls, postcards. (Box 12, Folder 27)
    - Dillon, Kathleen [21 of 31]1921 Oct. 1 - Nov. 20, Incl. als, tls, postcards. (Box 12, Folder 28)
    - Dillon, Kathleen [22 of 31]1921 Nov. 21 - Nov. 22, Incl. als, tls, postcards. (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Dillon, Kathleen [23 of 31]1921 Nov. 24 - Dec. 6, Incl. als, tls, postcards. (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Dillon, Kathleen [24 of 31]1921 Dec. 7 - 1924 May 6, Incl. als, tls, postcards. (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Dillon, Kathleen [25 of 31]1924 May 8 - August 16, Incl. als, tls, postcards. (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Dillon, Kathleen [26 of 31]1924 August 17 - August 24, Incl. als, tls, postcards. (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Dillon, Kathleen [27 of 31]1924 August 23 - Sept. 21, Incl. als, tls, postcards. (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Dillon, Kathleen [28 of 31]1924 Sept. 24 - Oct. 14, Incl. als, tls, postcards. (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Dillon, Kathleen [29 of 31]1924 Oct. 17 - Oct. 20, Incl. als, tls, postcards. (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Dillon, Kathleen [30 of 31]1924 Oct. 21 - Oct. 23, Incl. als, tls, postcards. (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Dillon, Kathleen [31 of 31]1925 Jan. 26 - July 12; n.d., Incl. als, tls, postcards. (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Dmowski, Roman, Count [1 of 11]1917 Jan. [n.d.] - May 27; n.d., Incl. a descriptive list, typescripts, a press cutting. (Box 13, Folder 11)
      Contains materials relating to Poplawski; Balicki; Kathleen Dillon; Count Zamoyski; M. Seyda; Ivan the Terrible; Maklakoff; Take Jonescu; Castellane; Vénizélos; Bratiano; Bismark; Gortschoff; Prince Carol of Romania; the Kaiser; Cardinal Gaspari; the Pope; Marsayh; Orlando; Hughes; Lloyd George; Wilson; Paderewski; Koltchak; Jean Jacques Finckelhals [?]; Welepolski.
      Dmowsky, Roman, Count
    - Dmowski, Roman, Count [2 of 11]1917 June 24 - 1918 Jan. 14; n.d., Incl. a descriptive list, typescripts, a press cutting. (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Dmowski, Roman, Count [3 of 11]1918 Jan. 18, Incl. a descriptive list, typescripts, a press cutting. (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Dmowski, Roman, Count [4 of 11]1918 Jan. 27 - March 16, Incl. a descriptive list, typescripts, a press cutting. (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Dmowski, Roman, Count [5 of 11]1918 May 1 - 1919 Jan. 10, Incl. a descriptive list, typescripts, a press cutting. (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Dmowski, Roman, Count [6 of 11]1919 [?] April 9 - 1919 April 29, Incl. a descriptive list, typescripts, a press cutting. (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Dmowski, Roman, Count [7 of 11]1919 June 8 - June 20, Incl. a descriptive list, typescripts, a press cutting. (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Dmowski, Roman, Count [8 of 11]1919 July 17 - Sept. 28, Incl. a descriptive list, typescripts, a press cutting. (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Dmowski, Roman, Count [9 of 11]1920 March 10 - March 12, Incl. a descriptive list, typescripts, a press cutting. (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Dmowski, Roman, Count [10 of 11]1921 Sept. 5, Incl. a descriptive list, typescripts, a press cutting. (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Dmowski, Roman, Count [11 of 11]1921 Nov. 18; n.d. / n.y., Incl. a descriptive list, typescripts, a press cutting. (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Doheny, Edward L. [1 of 4]1919 May 29 - August 30; n.d., Incl. a descriptive list, tls, press cuttings. (Box 13, Folder 22)
      Contains materials relating to General Obregon; Mr. Charles E. Hughes; Mrs. Dillon; Mrs. Doheny; Dr. Bridge; Senator Fall; Mr. Guy Stevens; Miss Varechine; Mr. Frank Seaver; Mr. Kelley; Mr. Watriss; Mr. Kellogg; Mr. Walker; President Carranza; Justice Butler; Mr. Harry Sinclair; Senator Walsh; Senator Borah; Mr. Coolidge; Robert M. La Follette; Senator Nye; Senator Norris; Daugherty; H.S. Oster; Owen J. Roberts; Atlee Pomerene; Mrs. C.C. Chase.
    - Doheny, Edward L. [2 of 4]1919 Sept. 15 - 1921 June 15, Incl. a descriptive list, tls, press cuttings. (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Doheny, Edward L. [3 of 4]1921 June 20 - 1928 April 4, Incl. a descriptive list, tls, press cuttings. (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - Doheny, Edward L. [4 of 4]1927 Oct. 26 - 1930 March 23, Incl. a descriptive list, tls, press cuttings. (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - Domashevskaia, Olgan.d. (Box 13, Folder 26)
      Contains correspondence in Russian relating to Iuriev, the former editor of "Russkaia Mysl'; Mordovtseff; Kalmykova; Aleksandra Mikhailovna.
      Domashevskaya, Ol'ga
    - Dombrovskaia, Olga1911 Feb. 5 (Box 13, Folder 27)
      Contains correspondence in Russian relating to Turgenev; B. Shaw; Wells; Fet; Nekrasov; Leskov; Gorkii; Tolstoi; Artsybashev; Kropnitskii; Stepan Razin; Pougachev; Bakunin; Andreev; Marx; O. Wilde; Dryden; Hobbes.
      Dombrovskaia, Ol'ga
    - Dunraven, [?], Lord1919 April 19; n.d. / n.y., Incl. tls. (Box 13, Folder 28)
      Contains correspondence relating to Mr. Patrick Conmie; Captain Moir; Mrs. Dillon.
    - Duranty, Waltern.d. (Box 13, Folder 29)
    - Durnovo, P.1908 May 21 - 1912 Jan. 13; n.y. (Box 13, Folder 30)
    - Dzhelal, M.1912 June 16 - June 19; n.d., Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 14, Folder 1)
      In French and Turkish.
    - Dziembowki, [?]1902 Feb. 13, Incl. a descriptive list, als [?]. (Box 14, Folder 2)
      In German.
    - Eddine, Sabah, Prince1911 [?] July 11; n.d. (Box 14, Folder 3)
      Eddine, Sabbah, Prince
    - Edward VII, King1902 Oct. 25, Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 14, Folder 4)
      Contains materials relating to Queen Alexandra.
    - Eeden, Frederik [?], Van, Dr. [1 of 4]1899 Nov. 17 - 1901 August 16, Incl. tls, postcards, a card, a typescript. (Box 14, Folder 5)
      Contains materials relating to Prince Kropotkin; Mrs. G.W. Van Eeden Everts; Father Gapon; Lady Welby; Wolmanns; Wessels; Sir Edward; Mr. Lawson; Boers [?]; the Tsar; Witte; Mr. Baerlein; M.b. Suzuki; Multatuli (Eduard Dekker); Van Deyssel (Alberdingk Thym); Netscher; Leo Tolstoi; Goethe. Some materials are in German.
    - Eeden, Frederik [?], Van, Dr. [2 of 4]1901 Sept. 6 - 1906 Sept. 6 [?], Incl. tls, postcards, a card, a typescript. (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Eeden, Frederik [?], Van, Dr. [3 of 4]1907 [?] July 4 [?] - 1931 Dec. 31, Incl. tls, postcards, a card, a typescript. (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Eeden, Frederik [?], Van, Dr. [4 of 4]1932 July 8; n.d., Incl. tls, postcards, a card, a typescript. (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Egan, Patrick1905 Oct. 5, Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Elizabeth, Queen of Romania1913 Oct. 18 - 1926 Dec. 1; n.d., Incl. a card, an offprint. (Box 14, Folder 10)
      Contains materials relating to Madame Bratiano; Madame Dillon; Mr. Clarence W. Barron; R.M. S. Berengaria; Prince Nicholas; Princess Ileana; Mr. W. Ballyn; Miss Glenn Ellyn. Some materials are in French.
      Elisabeth, Queen of Romania
    - Elliot, Charles, Sir1888 April 25 / May 7 - 1903 Nov. 11; n.d., Incl. als [?]. (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Ellis, Arthur1902 Feb. 25, Tls. (Box 14, Folder 12)
      Contains materials relating to Sir Edward Lawson; Lord Chamberlain.
    - Eutaxias, Ath.1909 Dec. 6 - Dec. 19; n.d., Incl. a descriptive list, tls. (Box 14, Folder 13)
      Some materials are in German.
    - Falla, Manuel, De.1922 Nov. 7 - 1929 [?] March [?] [n.d.] (Box 14, Folder 14)
      In Spanish.
    - Farrell, R.U. [?]1923 Dec. 4, Incl. a descriptive list, tls. (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Fasciotti, [?] [1 of 2]1913 Sept. 21 - Oct. 25 (Box 14, Folder 16)
      Contains materials relating to Monsieur T. Jonesco; S.E. Barone Aliotti, Italian Minister. Some materials are in French and Italian.
    - Fasciotti, [?] [2 of 2]1913 Nov. 3 - 1914 April 20; n.d. (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Fennel, Adolph D.1920 Sept. 18 (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Ferraris, Maggiorino [?]1916 Sept. [?] 22, Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 14, Folder 19)
      In Italian.
    - Filippi, Caroline, Den.d., Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Firstenberg, Boris Alekseevich1921 Nov. 3 - 1924 Nov. 11 (Box 14, Folder 21)
      Containsa correspondence in Russian relating to Elizaveta Aleksandrovna Firstenberg [H.-F.]; B. Ts. S.
      Fürstenberg, Boris Alekseevich
    - Fitzgerald, C.1894 Feb. [?] 3 [?], Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - Flint, Chas. R.1908 May 22 - 1924 March 8, Tls. (Box 14, Folder 23)
      Contains materials relating to Mr. Alexandre Borisoff; Mr. Melville E. Stone; Minister Bahkmeteff; Count Witte; Mrs. Flint; Mrs. Dillon; Cobb.
    - Forbes, Rosita1930 Jan. 23; n.y., Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - Forille, [?], Den.d., Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - França, Jose Nestor, De1879 June 25 - August [?] 2, Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 14, Folder 26)
    - Frew, Robert, Rev.1912 May 26, Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 14, Folder 27)
    - Frewen, E.J.[n.y.] Oct. 13 (Box 14, Folder 28)
    - Frewen, Moreton [1 of 2]1913 Feb. 2 - 1917 May 11; n.y., Incl. tls. (Box 14, Folder 29)
      Contains materials relating to Lord Morley; Lord Wolverton; Mr. Gladstone; Chamberlain; Crewe; Lord Dunraven; Lord Grey; Sheridan; Mrs. Lindsay; Joffre; Lord Milner.
    - Frewen, Moreton [2 of 2]n.d. / n.y., Incl. tls. (Box 14, Folder 30)
    - Fukushima, Y., General1902 [?] April 29; n.d. (Box 14, Folder 31)
    - Gapon, Georgii, Father [1 of 7]1905 Jan. 9 / 22 - 1909 Jan. 26 / Feb. 8, Incl. a descriptive list, press cuttings, a book, manuscripts, typescripts, offprints. (Box 15, Folder 1)
      Contains materials relating to the Tsar [the Emperor Nikolai II]; Azef; Ruthenberg; P.I. Rachkovskii; Count Witte; Prince Sviatopolk-Mirskii; Kokovtseff; Maxim Gorkii; Prof. Kareieff [Karevoff ?]; Messrs. Miakotin; Annenskii; Hessen; Peshekhonoff; Arsenieff; Assistant MInister Rydzeffskii; Priest Sergius; Grand Duke Vladimir; Evgenii Kedrin; Prince Kropotkin; Gorchakoff; Father Antonin; Sokoloff; Philippoff; Ornatskii; Prince Potemkin; M. Plehve; General Foulon. Some materials are in Russian and German.
    - Gapon, Georgii, Father [2 of 7]1905 Jan. 23, Incl. a descriptive list, press cuttings, a book, manuscripts, typescripts, offprints. (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Gapon, Georgii, Father [3 of 7]1905 Jan. 23, Incl. a descriptive list, press cuttings, a book, manuscripts, typescripts, offprints. (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Gapon, Georgii, Father [4 of 7]1905 Jan. 23, Incl. a descriptive list, press cuttings, a book, manuscripts, typescripts, offprints. (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Gapon, Georgii, Father [5 of 7]1905 March 10 - 1909 Sept. 22, Incl. a descriptive list, press cuttings, a book, manuscripts, typescripts, offprints. (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Gapon, Georgii, Father [6 of 7]1909 Feb. 16 / March 1 - 1914 March 1 / 14, Incl. a descriptive list, press cuttings, a book, manuscripts, typescripts, offprints. (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Gapon, Georgii, Father [7 of 7]1914 [?] - 1932 August [?] [n.d.], Incl. a descriptive list, press cuttings, a book, manuscripts, typescripts, offprints. (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Garibaldi, Ricciolli, General1897 May 3; n.d., Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 15, Folder 8)
      One material us in French.
    - Garth, Alma1905 Oct. 1 - 1906 [?] July 14 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Garvin, J.M.1903 [?] August 29 [?] - 1925 July 15, Incl. tls. (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Gennadius, John [1 of 3]1910 Jan. 11 / 24 - March 12, Incl. a descriptive list, tls, typescripts. (Box 15, Folder 11)
      Contaisn materials relating to Nicholas J. Coundouris; Mr. Venezelous [Venizelos]; George Gennadius of Epirus; Lord Rosebery; Mr. Coschen; Samuel Laing; Florence Gennadius.
      Gennadius, Joannes
    - Gennadius, John [2 of 3]1910 March 26 - 1915 Jan. [?] 28, Incl. a descriptive list, tls, typescripts. (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Gennadius, John [3 of 3]n.d. / n.y., Incl. a descriptive list, tls, typescripts. (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - George, David Lloyd [1 of 3]1917 Feb. 1 [?] - April 13, Incl. a descriptive list, tls. (Box 15, Folder 14)
      Contaisn materials relating to Mr. Davies; Robespierre; Prof. Nicolas Basilesco; Mr. Kerr; Mrs. Dillon.
    - George, David Lloyd [2 of 3]1917 Dec. 3 - 1919 Jan. 16, Incl. a descriptive list, tls. (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - George, David Lloyd [3 of 3]1919 May 20 - 1924 July 10, Incl. a descriptive list, tls. (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Georgiades, [A. / D. ?]1897 [month ?] 4 / 16 - Oct. 4, Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Géraud, André1910 May 27, Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Gherwont, Archbishop1895 May 15 / 27 - 1897 Jan. 10, Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 15, Folder 19)
      Gherwont [Shishmanian], Archbishop; Gherwont [Shishmanyan], Archbishop
    - Gie, Nikolai N.[1892 - 1893 ?] April 2 (Box 15, Folder 20)
      Contains correspondence in Russian relating to Nikolai Semenovich Leskoff.
      Gei, Nikolai N.; Gay, Nikolai N.
    - Giolitti, Giovanni1916 [?] July [?] 20, Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - Gladstone, William E. [1 of 2]1893 June 13 - 1895 Sept. 16, Incl. a press cutting, an offprint. (Box 15, Folder 22)
      Contains materials relating to Lord Salisbury; Baron de Kallay; Sir Philip Currie; the Sultan; Lord Kimberley; Mostigo; Percy W. Bunting.
    - Gladstone, William E. [2 of 2]1895 August 8 [?] - Dec. 21, Incl. a press cutting, an offprint. (Box 15, Folder 23)
    - Gohier, Urbain189 [?] [month ?] 17; n.d. / n.y. (Box 15, Folder 24)
    - Goodman, E.L., Esq.1910 April 7, Incl. a descriptive list, tls. (Box 15, Folder 25)
      Contains materials relating to Izvolskii; the German Ambassador.
    - Gotberg, Ya. M.1896 Nov. 5, Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 15, Folder 26)
      Contains materials in Russian relating to Le Sage; Prince Lobanov.
    - Graham-Esmonde, H., Sir, M.P.1890 Nov. 18 - 1891 June 19; n.d. (Box 15, Folder 27)
    - Graves, R.W. [1 of 2]1895 Feb. 6 - Feb. 27; n.d., Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 15, Folder 28)
      Contains correspondence relating to Mrs. Dillon; Richardson; Sir P. Currie; Mr. Scudatore. Some materials are in French and German.
    - Graves, R.W. [2 of 2]1895 Feb. 23 - May 12, Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 15, Folder 29)
    - Greene, George A.1890 Dec. 14 - 1892 Sept. 23, Incl. a descriptive list, an offprint. (Box 15, Folder 30)